Finding Aids to Personal Papers and Special Collections in the VMFA Archives Leslie Cheek, Jr. Personal Papers, 1931-1993 SC-02
VMFA Archives
Leslie Cheek, Jr. Personal Papers
1931-1993
VMFA Archives
Cheek, Leslie, 1908-
Temple, K. Richmond
Rouse, Parke, 1915-1997
SC-02
19.4 Linear Feet 16 boxes; 596 folders and 48 oversized items
This collection documents a small portion of the dynamic life of Leslie Cheek, Jr., the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts' second and longest-tenured Director (1948-1968). One series includes material from his early career and activities before the VMFA, as well as his tenure at the museum, and through his active retirement. Two series document the publication of two photobiographies about Cheek, "Living by Design" and "Designing for the Arts." Another series is comprised of materials about Skylark Farm, the house and tree farm located in the Blue Ridge Mountains, owned, designed and furnished by the Cheeks between 1967 and 1977 when it was donated to Washington and Lee University. Other series document the Cheeks' personal world travels in the 1950s-1980s, some of Cheek's many achievement awards, and finally, a number of framed architectural drawings done by Cheek as a student in the 1930s.
Box SC-02 Box 1
Box SC-02 Box 2
Box SC-02 Box 3
Box SC-02 Box 4
Box SC-02 Box 5
Box SC-02 Box 6
Box SC-02 Box 7
Box SC-02 Box 8
Box SC-02 Box 13
Box SC-02 Box 14
Box SC-02 Box 15
Box SC-02 Box 16
Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 1
Oversize SC-02 Flat Files 2
Oversize SC-02 Hanging Location 1
Oversize SC-02 Hanging Location 2
Oversize SC-02 Hanging Location 3
Oversize SC-02 Realia 1
Provenance
This collection is comprised of materials donated by Leslie Cheek, Jr.'s family members. The bulk of this collection was donated to the VMFA Library by Leslie's widow Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek McClenahan in 1993. The remainder of the material was donated by Leslie's children in 2005.
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research. A limited number of files are restricted. Access to restricted materials may require written permission of the donor and/or the VMFA Director.
Biographical Note
Leslie Cheek, Jr. was the second and longest-tenured Director of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts. During his 20 year Directorship (1948-1968), he transformed the museum from a regional gem to museum that operated on the international stage.
Born in Nashville, Cheek was the son of Mabel Wood and Leslie Cheek, Sr., who became rich by investing in the family formula for Maxwell House Coffee. Cheek studied art at Harvard University before taking up architecture at Yale University and Columbia. After graduation, he headed to William and Mary College where he founded and headed up the Department of Fine Arts from 1937-1939. In 1939, he married Richmonder Mary Tyler Freeman, daughter of Pulitzer Prize winning author Douglas Southall Freeman. From 1939-1942, Cheek served in his first Directorship at the Baltimore Museum of Fine Art. He left the museum in 1942 to join the Army Corps of Engineers in WWII.
After the war, he was hired as the Associate Editor of Architectural Forum Magazine and lived in New York City for three years. In 1948, he came to the VMFA as Director, spending 20 years building the collections, endowments, and reputation of the museum. He was best known for the Artmobile, a mobile art program which brought the museum's collections all over the state of Virginia, and the Virginia Museum Theatre which opened in 1955 and successfully integrated the performing and visual arts.
After retiring in 1968, Cheek stayed very active in the arts, and two books were published about his life and career, "Living by Design" and "Designing for the Arts." In 1967, the Cheeks purchased a mountaintop home named Skylark Farm in the Blue Ridge Mountains, which they donated to Washington and Lee University in 1977.
(The above information was taken from the website "The Dictionary of Art Historians" and Virginia Commonwealth University's online "Guide to the Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek McClenahan Papers.")
Scope and Content Note
The collection's inclusive dates are 1931-1993, with the bulk of the material dating from the 1960s-1980s. The collection is comprised of correspondence, plans, photographs, financial records, interviews, book drafts, exhibition records, travel itineraries, and other ephemeral material.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into six series, folders are arranged in the original order maintained by Cheek, and retain their original folder titles when provided.
Series 1: Skylark Farm, 1966-1992
Series 2: "Living by Design" and "Cheek and the Arts," 1945-1989
Series 3: "Designing for the Arts," 1984-1991
Series 4: Personal Files, 1934-1992
Series 5: Awards and Degrees, 1931-1993
Series 6: Trips, 1952-1980
Related Materials - VMFA Library: Books
Ten Talents in the American Theatre, 1957
Living by Design: Leslie Cheek and the Arts, 1985
Designing for the Arts: Environments by Leslie Cheek, 1990
Southern Civility: Recollections of my Early Life, 2003
Related Materials - VMFA Library: Exhibition File
Drawings for the Stage by Leslie Cheek, Jr., 1987
Related Materials - VMFA Library: Subject File
VMFA Directors: Leslie Cheek Jr. (4 folders)
Related Materials - Library of Virginia
Virginia Museum of Fine Arts Director's Correspondence, 1936-1976 (Coll. No. 33863 and 44067)
Virginia Museum of Fine Arts Exhibition Files, 1936-1992 (Coll No. 31633, 32958, 33041, 33160, 34679, 36342, 36957 and 37636)
Related Materials - Other Institutions
Archives of American Art, Washington, DC: Architectural Forum, 1945-47; Time Lab, 1946-47; House Beautiful, 1947; Forum Exhibits, 1946-48; Exhibition Houses, Architectural Forum, 1947; Architectural League; Beauty at the Bar, Architectural League, 1948; Life in USA Houses Speech, Architectural League, 1946; Baltimore Museum Files: Correspondence, Photographs, Exhibition Info and Brochures; Architectural Consultant Files, 1968 to 1992; Above It All (Yale Thesis); Camouflage Info, Fort Belvoir, early 40's; For Us the Living (microfilm, original at MOMA); Oral History Interview
College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, VA: Photographs of Stage Sets; Articles; Festival Theatre; Publicity for Theatre Development; Publicity for Frobenius; Cheek Award; O'Keefe Affair; Muscarelle Museum; Competition Show; Publicity for Stage Design Exhibitions; WandM Coat-of-Arms; Tom Sawyer Exhibition; Publicity for Frank Lloyd Wright Show; Washington Speech; 19th Century Party; Faraway Farm Information; Drawings of Stage Sets related to WandM (Phi Beta Hall; Taliaferro Hall, Parties)
Museum of Modern Art, New York City, NY: For Us the Living Exhibition
Robert E. Lee Memorial Association, Stratford, VA: The Bounty; Planters; Postcard Info: Footbridge, Library, Tobacco Planter; Gas Logs; Art for Stratford; Post Lanterns; Judge DeHardit; Cruise on the Potomac; Painting Air View by Harry Robertson; Jackie Onassis; Hydrofoil; Swans; Brook; Trans Art; Umbrella Stand; Virginia Cabin; Maxwell Hamish Correspondence; Signs; Snapshots; Correspondence with Nancy Lancaster, Marian Young, Dottie Follansbee, John Wall, Jane Hanahan, Mrs. Robert Isham, Mrs. Joe Hume Gardner, Tom Bass
Queens Museum, New York City, NY: Drawings of the 1939 New York World's Fair (Virginia Room)
Virginia Historical Society, Richmond, VA: Four Camouflage Training Displays (Ft. Belvoir – early 40's); Rotunda Club History
Art museum directors -- Virginia; Art -- Virginia -- Richmond -- History; Art -- Virginia -- Richmond -- Exhibition techniques -- History; Theater -- United States -- History; Cheek, Leslie, 1908-; McClenahan, Mary Tyler Freeman Cheek, 1917-; Temple, K. Richmond; Rouse, Parke, 1915-1997; Yale University; Joseph and Margaret Muscarelle Museum of Art‏; Virginia Museum of Fine Arts; Skylark Farm; Washington and Lee University
- Series 1: Skylark Farm, 1966-1992; SC-02-01; 197 folders;; 2 items
  Series Description
  This series is comprised of correspondence, plans, and photographs related to Skylark Farm, a house and tree farm located in the Blue Ridge Mountains of Virginia, owned, designed and furnished by the Cheeks between 1967 and 1977 when it was donated to Washington and Lee University. The Cheeks were also involved in the transformation of the house into a conference center for the University in the 1990s.
  - Property acquisition: maps, deeds, correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 1)
  - Property acquisition: correspondence with D. Alen Penick, attorney, 1966-1967 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 2)
  - Skylark Farm construction: correspondence with architects, 1967-1968 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 3)
  - Property acquisition: correspondence with Penick, 1968 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 4)
  - Property acquisition: correspondence with Penick, 1969-1973 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 5)
  - Property acquisition: correspondence with Penick, 1974-1977 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 6)
  - Skylark Farm: proposal 10 year plan, undated (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 7)
  - Skylark: site plan, revised, Jan. 1968 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 8)
  - Skylark: plans, drawings, articles, Oct. 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 9)
  - Skylark: miscellaneous correspondence including floorplans, sections, realtors, Otis Mead, July 1985-Feb. 1991 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 10)
  - Skylark: correspondence with Robert Stewart, additions and architectural sketches, Mar. 1984-July 1987 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 11)
  - Skylark: design, blueprints for Skylark's roost, June 1986 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 12)
  - Skylark Farm: construction preparation, 1966-1967 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 13)
  - Road construction: maps and drawings, 1967-1971 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 14)
  - Skylark Farm: landscape architecture, Griswold, Winters, and Swain, 1968-1970 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 15)
  - Agricultural stabilization: conservation service, 1974-1977 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 16)
  - Road paving, Dec. 1972-July 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 17)
  - Soil and Montebello, weather, 1957-1967 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 18)
  - Excavation, Evers Brothers, Aug. 1972-Nov. 1974 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 19)
  - Soil conservation: correspondence with W. E. Friend, Jan. 1969-Dec. 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 20)
  - Skylark guest house addition: correspondence regarding conference center, 1983-1991 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 21)
  - Nurseries: correspondence, blueprints, plans, drawings, 1972-1977 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 22)
  - J. W. Harris: correspondence regarding surveying, mapping land, Mar. 1967-1978 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 23)
  - VPI Extension: planting Christmas trees, 1969-1972 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 24)
  - VPI Extension: planting Christmas trees, 1973-1977 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 25)
  - Garden layout, 1971 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 26)
  - Skylark Farm: landscape architecture, specifications, plans, drawings, undated (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 27)
  - Skylark Farm: flower and vegetable gardens, plans and orders, 1970 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 28)
  - Tree farm: plans, undated (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 29)
  - Christmas tree plantation plans, undated (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 30)
  - Christmas tree plantation II, undated (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 31)
  - Christmas tree sales, 1971-1977 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 32)
  - Christmas tree planting, 1968-1977 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 33)
  - Christmas tree appraisal and inventories, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 34)
  - Skylark Farm reforestation, 1973-1976 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 35)
  - Pond construction: drawings, plans, specifications, Mays and Sons, 1971-1972 (Box SC-02 Box 1, Folder Folder 36)
  - Fire protection equipment, 1970-1972 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 37)
  - Contractor John Snyder, 1972-1977 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 38)
  - Elevator system correspondence, June-Sep. 1967 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 39)
  - Fountain installation, Mar.-July 1971 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 40)
  - Engineers Sowers, Rodes and Whitescarver, July 1968-May 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 41)
  - Well and pump, Frank's Pump and Repair Shop, Apr. 1967-June 1972 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 42)
  - Chimney, N. W. Martin, Dec. 1970-Dec. 1973 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 43)
  - Trout pond, 1972-1975 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 44)
  - Contracts: pasture rental, June 1971-Nov. 1976 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 45)
  - Bomb shelter, undated (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 46)
  - Tenant house: operating and maintenance, July 1967-Apr. 1976 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 47)
  - Tenant house: construction, architect payment, correspondence with Robert Stewart, 1973-1974 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 48)
  - Tenant house: plans and drawings, undated (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 49)
  - Tenant house: construction, correspondence with perspective building contractors, 1971-1972 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 50)
  - Tenant house: construction, architect payment, correspondence with Robert Stewart, 1971 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 51)
  - Tenant house: construction, architect payment, correspondence with Robert Stewart, 1972 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 52)
  - Tenant house: furnishings, 1971 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 53)
  - Tenant house: furnishings, 1972-1973 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 54)
  - Tenant house: furnishings, Knoll International Inc., undated (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 55)
  - Tenant house: furnishings, Miller and Rhoads, undated (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 56)
  - Pond and dam construction: problems, correspondence with Penick and Mays, 1971-1973 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 57)
  - Manager's house: drawings and plans, also general site plans, 1967-1969 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 58)
  - Manager's house: construction, correspondence with architects, engineers, etc., 1967-1969 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 59)
  - Manager's house: correspondence with architects, Johnson, Craven, and Gibson, 1968 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 60)
  - Manager's house: correspondence with architects, engineers, etc., 1969 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 61)
  - Manager's house: construction, correspondence, J. B. Wine and Son, 1969-1970 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 62)
  - Manager's house: construction, architects' certificates and contractor requisitions, 1969-1970 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 63)
  - Manager's house: construction, correspondence with contractor J. B. Wine and Son, 1970 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 64)
  - Manager's house: construction, correspondence with architects, Johnson, Craven, and Gibson, 1969-1972 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 65)
  - Manager's house: construction problems, correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 66)
  - Manager's house: furnishings, Sep. 1967-Mar. 1970 (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 67)
  - Skylark Farm main house: drawings, interior, undated (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 68)
  - Skylark Farm weathervane, undated (Box SC-02 Box 2, Folder Folder 69)
  - Skylark: framing, letterhead design, drawings, serving trays, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 70)
  - Visitors to Skylark, June 1974-Aug. 1976 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 71)
  - Blueprint of site and directions, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 72)
  - Yardley screen: correspondence regarding acquiring from VMFA, Oct. 1983-Jan. 1984 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 73)
  - Skylark Farm: site plans, maps, aerial view, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 74)
  - Tenant house #2: drawings and plans, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 75)
  - Tenant house #2: construction, correspondence with Robert Stewart, architect, 1976 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 76)
  - Tenant house #2: construction, architect payment, Robert Stewart, 1976-1977 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 77)
  - Tenant house #2: construction, correspondence with consulting engineers, Sowers, Rodes and Whitescarver, 1971-1973 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 78)
  - Tenant house #2: construction, correspondence with consulting engineers, Sowers, Rodes and Whitescarver, 1976-1977 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 79)
  - Tenant house #2: construction, correspondence with John Snyder, general contractor, 1976-1977 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 80)
  - Tenant house #2: construction, contractor payment, John Snyder, 1976-1977 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 81)
  - Tenant house #2: furnishings, Sears and J.C. Penney, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 82)
  - Tenant house #2: furnishings, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 83)
  - Skylark Farm: tax records, correspondence, assessments, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 84)
  - Skylark Farm: tennis court construction, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 85)
  - Skylark: instructions for signs and steps, Sep. 1988 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 86)
  - J. L. Heatwole, apple tree grafter, Sep. 1984-Apr. 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 87)
  - Skylark Farm: newspaper articles, publicity, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 88)
  - Skylark: Washington and Lee article by Richmond Temple, 1987-1988 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 89)
  - Skylark: correspondence and draft regarding Shenandoah Virginia Town and Country magazine, 1983-1985 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 90)
  - Postcard, unrealized dream house, proposed Washington and Lee conference center, Mar. 1990-Jan. 1992 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 91)
  - Correspondence with Artvue Color Postcard Company, Bill Bailey, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 92)
  - "Alterations and Additions to the Guest House, Skylark Farm for Washington and Lee University," Robert Stewart, Mar. 1990 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 93)
  - Washington and Lee: correspondence with James Whitehead, Dec. 1977-Oct. 1988 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 94)
  - Skylark: De Brady project, manager at Washington and Lee, repairs and maintenance, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 95)
  - Washington and Leave: correspondence with John D. Wilson, Nov. 1977-June 1992 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 96)
  - Cheek brochure on D. S. Freeman by Washington and Lee, Jan.-Aug. 1989 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 97)
  - Skylark: correspondence regarding brochure, Oct. 1989 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 98)
  - Correspondence: Farris Hotchkiss, 1980-1988 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 99)
  - Correspondence: Farris Hotchkiss, 1989 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 100)
  - Correspondence: Farris Hotchkiss, 1990-1992 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 101)
  - Skylark: miscellaneous correspondence, Oct. 1978-Aug. 1985 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 102)
  - Skylark: miscellaneous, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 103)
  - Big House: photographs of renderings and Bill Bailey painting, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 104)
  - Paintings by Bill Bailey: correspondence and photographs, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 105)
  - One set complete drawings: façade with elevation, undated (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 106)
  - Skylark ledger, 1971 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 107)
  - Skylark ledger, 1972 (Box SC-02 Box 3, Folder Folder 108)
  - Correspondence: J. R. Shelton, taxes and finance regarding Skylark, 1972-1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 109)
  - "Operating and Maintenance Instructions for the Equipment in 'The Tenant House and Shed'", undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 110)
  - Skylark: invoices, guest house addition, Robert Stewart, Whitescarver-Rodes, 1985-1991 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 111)
  - Skylark: gifts to Washington and Lee for Skylark furnishings, Feb.-Mar. 1982 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 112)
  - Skylark costs 1967: general (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 113)
  - Skylark costs 1967: accounting, lists by which books were originally set up, Dec. 1967 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 114)
  - Skylark costs 1967: architectural service (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 115)
  - Skylark costs 1967: Christmas tree project (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 116)
  - Skylark costs 1967: travel (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 117)
  - Skylark costs 1967: road (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 118)
  - Skylark costs 1967: soil conservation (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 119)
  - Skylark costs 1967: property search, Luray area (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 120)
  - Skylark costs 1967: trips, Autumn (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 121)
  - Skylark costs 1967: expense record (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 122)
  - Skylark costs 1968: fertilizer, lime (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 123)
  - Skylark costs 1968: gasoline, fuel and oil (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 124)
  - Skylark costs 1968: land costs (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 125)
  - Skylark costs 1968: insurance (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 126)
  - Skylark costs 1968: machine hire (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 127)
  - Skylark costs 1968: miscellaneous costs (other payments) (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 128)
  - Skylark costs 1968: purchases, seeds, plants (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 129)
  - Skylark costs 1968: rent of farm pasture (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 130)
  - Skylark costs 1968: repairs, etc. (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 131)
  - Skylark costs 1968: supplies (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 132)
  - Skylark costs 1968: taxes (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 133)
  - Skylark-photos and articles, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 134)
  - Skylark-interiors, guest house, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 135)
  - Skylark-interiors, main house, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 136)
  - Skylark Farm-deed, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 137)
  - Correspondence regarding gift to Washington and Lee, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 138)
  - J.R. Shelton, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 139)
  - Letters regarding gift, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 140)
  - Allen E. Penick, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 141)
  - Letters regarding gift to Washington and Lee, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 142)
  - Skylark, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 143)
  - Farm data, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 144)
  - Christmas Tree Plantation X, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 145)
  - Electricity-Skylark, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 146)
  - Fencing, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 147)
  - Gas, Fuel and Oil-Skylark, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 148)
  - Labor Costs, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 149)
  - Lime, Fertilizer, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 150)
  - Repairs, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 151)
  - Secretarial Services, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 152)
  - J.R. Shelton, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 153)
  - Supplies, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 154)
  - Telephone, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 155)
  - Checkbook, 1977 (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 156)
  - Skylark-appraisals, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 157)
  - Appraisal-Skylark-furniture, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 158)
  - Rockbridge Bank and Trust Co., undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 159)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 160)
  - Appraisal-Mead Associates, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 161)
  - Fees-related to gift appraisers, lawyers, real estate, surveyor, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 162)
  - Cost of fencing material, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 163)
  - Cost of lower apartment furnishings, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 164)
  - Cost of Tenant House #2 furnishings, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 165)
  - Appraisal-Valentine, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 166)
  - Costs-Skylark Farm, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 167)
  - Deed of gift, undated (Box SC-02 Box 4, Folder Folder 168)